所以当我们创建一个 MDX 文件时,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So
when we create an MDX file,
我要在我们的文档文件夹的主题 dev 中创建这个
and I'm gonna create this in our
theme dev in that docs folder, and
我们称之为索引，因为我想要一种主页，对不对？
we're just gnna call it index because
I want a kind of a homepage, right?
所以，编写 MDX 的默认方式是,
So, the default way of writing
MDX is we can just say,
你好，那是一个页面，对吗？
Hello and that's a page, right?
比如说可以在互联网上建一个网页。
Like that could be a page on the Internet.
我们想多加一点信息。
We wanna add a little more
information than that.
所以我要从一些前面的问题开始。
So I'm actually gonna start
with some front matter.
在 Markdown 中，前台工作的方式就是我们使用这些
And the way that front matter
works in Markdown is we use these
三重破折号是一种受保护的代码块。
triple dashes as a kind
of fenced code block.
然后我们使用 YAML 语法来说明我们的前端问题是什么。
And then we use YAML syntax to
say what our front matter is.
因此，我们需要一个名为 title 的字段出现在前面的问题上，并且
So we want a field called title
to show up on a front matter, and
这就是它的价值，这些都是随意的。
this will be what the value of it is and
these are arbitrary.
您可以在这里设置任何您想要的内容，大多数 YAML 语法应该可以工作。
You can set whatever you want in here and
most YAML syntax should work.
然后在我们的代码块下面，我们可以这样说，这些是文档！
And then below our code block,
we can say something like, These are docs!
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 为了保存它,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And on saving that,
我们有一个完全有效的 MDX 文件，可以任意使用。
we've got a completely valid MDX file
that we can use however we want.
所以，让我们把这个加载到网站使用的主题，以便我们可以显示它。
So let's get this loaded into the site
using the theme so that we can show it.
我们要做的第一件事就是
So the first thing that we're
gonna do is we're going to
在主题中加入一些东西。
install some things in the theme.
我们去纱线工作间盖茨比主题文件,
So we'll go yarn workspace
gatsby-theme-docs,
我们将添加 gatsby-source-file-system。
and we will add
the gatsby-source-file-system.
盖茨比源文件系统所做的就是它允许我们使用
And what Gatsby-source-file-system
does is it allows us to use
项目本身中的一个文件夹作为数据源。
a folder in the project
itself as a data source.
因此它将把它放在 GraphQL 层中，这样我们就可以使用它做一些事情。
So it'll put it in the GraphQL layer so
we can do stuff with it.
然后我们将使用 gatsby-plugin-mdx 和
Then we're going to use
gatsby-plugin-mdx and
将要做的是它将寻找
what Gatsby plugin MDX
will do is it'll look for
任何点 MDX 类型的文件它会将它们转换为 MDX 节点,
any files that are of the type dot MDX And
it will convert them into MDX nodes,
也就是说我们可以得到文件的内容。
which means that we can get
at the content of that file.
然后 gatsby-plugin-mdx 有一些依赖性，所以
And then gatsby-plugin-mdx
has some dependencies, so
我们需要使用 mdx-js / mdx 包
we need to use the mdx-js/mdx package and
然后我们还需要使用 mdx-js / react 包。
then we also need to use
the mdx-js/react package.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 所以我们将安装它们。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So
we'll get those installed.
现在，我们可以配置这些
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And now,
we can get those configured
在我们的盖茨比-配置的主题。
in our gatsby-config for the theme.
所以我们要创建一个盖茨比配置旁边的我们
So we're gonna create
a gatsby-config next to our
盖茨比节点，杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 和
gatsby-node,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And
再说一次，我们要模块化，出口。
again, we're going to do module.exports.
现在编写配置文件的标准方法是
Now the standard way that you would
write a config file is you would have
只是一个物体，对吗？
just an object, right?
但是因为我们在一个主题中，这个函数就变成了一个接收这些选项的函数。
But because we're in a theme, this becomes
a function that receives those options.
因为我们在接收选项，所以我们想使用我们的默认值。
And because we're receiving options,
we wanna use our defaults.
所以让我们导入，我们要导入默认值，并要求实用文件。
So let's import that, we're gonna import
with defaults and require utility file.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 所以在这里我们将得到我们需要的东西。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And so up here
we're going to get the things we need.
所以我们要使用 contentPath，因为我们需要告诉文件系统在哪里查找
So we're gonna use the contentPath cuz we
need to tell the file system where to look
我们将使用外部 MDX，因为我们需要知道
and we're going to use external MDX
because we need to know whether or
我们不应该加载 MDX 插件内的主题。
not we should load the MDX
plugin inside the theme.
所以我们会说 withDefaults (options) ,
So we'll say withDefaults(options),
然后我们可以返回我们的配置对象。
and then we can return our config object.
在这种情况下，我们只是要返回一些插件。
And in this case,
we're just gonna return some plugins.
总是使用第一种方法，即解析 gatsby-source-file-system。
The first one is always gonna be used and
that is resolve gatsby-source-file-system.
Jason Lengstorf: 我们首先要发送的选项是 name 和
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And the options
that we wanna send it first is name, and
我将使用插件的名称。
I'm gonna use the plugin name.
我们会在一分钟内讨论为什么，但是一般的想法
And we'll talk more about why in a minute,
but the general idea
我们希望能够识别这个主题加载了哪些文件。
is that we wanna be able to identify
which files were loaded by this theme.
因为当我们用它来创建页面时,
Because when we go to
create pages from it,
如果另一个主题使用 MDX，我们不希望创建文档页面
if another theme uses MDX, we wouldn't
want to create docs pages out of
一些博客主题，MDX 文件。
some a blog themes, MDX files.
我们想从 contentPath 上抓取这些信息。
And we wanna grab those
from the contentPath.
因此，这将为我们提供文件系统中需要的文件。
So, this will give us the files
that we want in our file system.
还有，詹森 · 兰斯托夫: 让我们
And,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Let's
把减价券拿过来。
get the Markdown here.
所以我们将使用 externalmdx。
So we'll go useExternalMDX.
因此，如果 useExternalMDX 设置为 true，我们将跳过整个步骤。
So if useExternalMDX is set to true
we're just gonna skip this whole step.
这就是我们要检查的。
So that's what we're checking here.
所以如果它是假的,
And so if it is false,
我们会说 resolve gatsby-plugin-mdx
we're going to say resolve
gatsby-plugin-mdx and
对于选项，我们将使用 defaultLayouts。
for the options,
we will use defaultLayouts.
我们还没有定义这个，但是我们要为
And we haven't defined this yet, but
we're gonna set up a default layout for
我们的 MDX 文件。
our MDX files.
这意味着当我们加载 MDX 文件时，Gatsby 会查找
And what this means is that when we load
an MDX file, Gatsby is going to look for
这个包装器组件，并将 MDX 文件放入其中。
this wrapper component and
put the MDX files inside of it.
这给了我们一个控制输出的方法
And that gives us a way
to control the output
而不需要在 MDX 文件本身中编写一堆自定义代码。
without having to write a bunch of custom
code inside of the MDX files themselves.
因此我们将把它放在 source / components / layout. js 中。
And so we will put that at
source/components/layout.js.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 最后，一旦我们到了这里,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And
finally, once we get down here,
因为这有可能是假的,
because there's a chance
that this is gonna be false,
我们要过滤我们的插件数组，因为我们要确保我们
we are going to filter our plugin array
because we wanna make sure that we
不要只送回一个会使盖茨比抱怨的虚假价值。
don't send back just a false value
that'll cause Gatsby to complain.
所以我们要过滤布尔值，让它去掉所有假值。
So we're gonna filter for Boolean so
that it drops any false values.
这么说有点老生常谈
That's kind of a hacky
way to say like if it
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 但是我真的很喜欢这个
exists
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: But I really like this
当你做这种事的时候，为了保持简洁。
as a way of kind of keeping it terse
when you're doing that sort of thing.